

Simon Durbridge

Embedded Audio Research & Development



Linkedin



https://sedurcode.com



Researchgate



Github



durbridge123@googlemail.com

Awards -

- •AES Student Research Award 2016,
- Best Presentation UoY EE PhD Conference 2019

Skill

Software Development

Audio Signal Processing

Independent Research

Software Optimisation

Algorithm Development

C++ (Sharc flavour 11ish)

Modern C++ (17++)

High Level Languages (Python, Matlab)

Machine Learning

Linux Kernel Driver Development

(*)[The skill scale is a relative representation of my confidence in these areas from 'Chat-GPT assisted' to 'Boris Grishenko'.]

About Me

I am a specialist signal processing software engineer, a postgraduate research student, a keen climber and a closet musician. When I'm not working on low level optimisations or high level abstractions, I am exploring the natural and technological world.

Education

Ending May 2023	PhD candidate in Electronic Engineering Physiological Measures in Immersive La. Evaluation	-
2015-2017	M.Sc. Audio Engineering Efficient Acoustic Modelling of Large Spamerical Methods	University of Derby aces using Time Domain Nu-
2011-2015	B.Sc. Sound, Light & Live Event Techno The Effects of Distortion on Perceived Lo	
2006-2008	BTEC Music Performance Specializing in guitar performance	Academy of Contemporary Music

Experience

since 2019 Freelance

Specialist Digital Signal Processing Consultant

- · Providing audio signal processing consultancy to several
- · Primary Client: Neural DSP Technologies
- Sharc/ARM/x86 programming, C++, JUCE, Assembler, Python, Bash, Qt, Linux
- · Algorithm porting, implementation & optimisation
- · Multi-SoC system programming
- · Working across international remote teams

2017-2019 **Bowers & Wilkins**

DSP Engineer

- Develop and maintain bespoke audio processing algorithms and other supplementary programs
- · ADI Sigma DSP (Assembler), Matlab, Python, Bash
- · Work with international teams across the organisation
- · Responsible for performing research and analysis of the digital audio signal path, working to steer decisions based on signal integrity and quality
- · Tasked with developing, prototyping and exploring the future of audio signal processing platforms and processes

2015-2017 Amina Technologies **Development Engineer**

- Developed product manufacturing automation
- Improved product testing processes
- Collaborated on new products

2009-2017 Freelance Audio Engineer

- · Live event production, sound engineering, lighting
- · Building temporary demountable structures and rigging
- · Equipment organisation, truck loading, testing
- Van driving
- · High pressure time critical problem solving
- Client liaison, budgeting and event specification

[Interests]

Music Production, Embedded Systems, Human Perception, Physics, Video Games Programming, Rock Climbing, DIY Technology, 3D Printing, Music Technology.